[The Ingenious One]
[Episode 4: Acquiring Liansheng House]
Please wait here for a moment.
OK.
What an important guest to Guanghui Bank!
[Mo Bufan, Yuntai Sect]
"In the snowy mountains lies a noble man."
"Out of the moonlit forest comes a beauty."
Hello, Mr. Mo.
I wonder which one you look forward to,
a beauty, or a noble man?
A noble man is dull, and a beauty is distractive.
I want neither of them.
I didn't expect you, Master's last disciple
and taken in as an exception,
would be so young and handsome.
I am still a novice
and would appreciate your kind help.
This gentleman looks like no ordinary man.
Is he a fellow disciple?
Mr. Kang,
meet your senior and fellow disciple, Mr. Yun.
I'm Yun Xiang.
Kang Qiao.
Come on, have a seat.
Come on.
As soon as you came to town,
I sorted out all of Wen Cong's accounts
in Nandu.
You came to Nandu
for these, right?
You're indeed very resourceful, Mr. Mo.
I suppose it would be against the rules
for me to take away these ledgers.
Of course.
Don't worry, chum.
Take your time.
It's OK.
I developed a photographic memory
a long time ago at Yuntai.
Of what happened to Mr. Wen...
Are you aware?
Nourishing a viper in his bosom
was exactly what Wen Cong had been doing.
Was there anyone behind Qi Tianfeng?
Have you ever wondered
why I was not involved
in this Wen Cong incident?
I'm puzzled indeed.
Confidentiality is of top priority for Yuntai.
Wen Cong was in charge of the affairs of Nandu.
I collect information and pass on messages.
I never asked about his affairs.
And he never asked about mine.
No wonder this tragedy happened to Mr. Wen.
Resourceful though you are, Mr. Mo,
you were not at all alert to it.
Now I see.
I suppose these old accounts of Mr. Wen's
do need some looking into.
You could've offered some help, kid!
That man was really taught by Master himself?
Not only that,
normally disciples stayed for 3 to 5 years,
but Master kept him by his side for over 10 years.
You see how highly he was thought of?
That's strange.
He was shadowed by people of the Cao Sect today
but didn't seem to be aware of it.
Are you sure
[Everlasting Loyalty]
that Jin Biao is not with him?
It's true.
And the woman?
She left alone early in the morning.
Go gather the best men in the sect.
OK.
Yun Xiang went straight to Liansheng House
and then Guanghui Bank
after arriving in Nandu.
Do you realize what it means?
He's planning to resume Wen Cong's business?
You say you're Wen Cong's goddaughter.
But why should we believe you?
I've answered this question many times today.
Where is this crazy woman from?
After this insult, you'll ask me for the IOU.
If I can't present it,
you'll say I have no evidence to prove
that you owe my godfather money, right?
I'm only being reasonable.
If I keep pestering you,
you'll ask these servants to kick me out.
After I knock them down one by one,
you'll show me a receipt and claim that
you paid it back to Guanghui Bank long ago.
Guanghui Bank only took 70%.
They gave you the rest as hush money, right?
I'm really tired from all the fighting.
Will you just give me back the IOU
so we can skip the violence?
Kick this crazy woman out!
Alright, ma'am. Alright.
I'll go get it.
[Jishan Hall]
Warrior Jin, this way please.
Honey, we have an important guest.
It's Warrior Jin, aka "Ten Taels of Gold"!
Warrior Jin!
Thank you so much
for your monthly donations to the orphans in Jishan Hall.
I'd like to thank you on behalf of them.
Not at all.
I'm only contributing some money.
You two are doing the real work.
You're too modest.
Come on have a seat.
-Take a rest and have some tea. -Have a seat.
The kids are doing well?
Yes.
Why is it so quiet in here?
[Jia Chang'an, Jishan Hall]
[Mrs. Jia, Jishan Hall]
Warrior Jin,
you're apparently
a man with no experience with kids.
At this time of the day,
they're having their nap after lunch.
I'm not able to take care of the orphan
that was entrusted to me.
Thankfully there is Jishan Hall.
You're too kind.
I'll get you the ledger.
No, wait.
I'll leave the details to you two.
You must take a look.
Wait...
Here, Warrior Jin.
You're Jishan Hall's biggest benefactor.
We would feel more at ease
if you can be aware of how the money is spent.
Yeah.
Please have a look.
I-It's all very clear.
Very clear.
Since the kids are asleep,
I'll come back some other time.
Goodbye.
Take care.
-Warrior Jin, I'll see you out. -No need.
Why aren't you asleep?
Did our talking wake you up?
Come on.
What's your name?
Her name is Xiaoyu.
Xiaoyu?
Xiaoyu, say hello to Mr. Jin.
This is the benefactor I told you about.
Please excuse her, Warrior Jin.
She's just a kid
and gets shy in front of strangers.
I will teach them manners in the future.
Never mind.
It's OK.
Be good and eat well. I'll come by again.
I hope you'll be sturdier then.
You heard that?
I'm a bit hard up at the moment.
I'll bring you the money as soon as I have it.
There's no rush.
I'm off.
Warrior Jin, I'll see you out.
He's left.
Far enough?
Yes.
I'll beat the living daylights out of you!
Stop it now!
We'll have to buy another feather duster
if this one breaks.
Our priority now
is figuring out how to deal with Jin.
What's there to fear?
Those kids have been sold anyway.
There's no changing that.
We'll come up with something.
Enough with the staring! Come out now!
Listen,
if you don't behave yourself,
I'll break your legs!
Got it?
Don't! I won't do it again.
[Jishan Hall]
Bravo!
Do you want it?
No.
-Are you okay? -I’m fine.
Thank you, sir.
Master Kui.
Is everyone here?
All is set as you ordered.
Master Kui,
it's such a clever tactic you're employing.
Fireworks!
Sir, have a look at these fireworks.
There's a whole range of them to choose from.
-All kinds of fun. -No, thanks.
Which kind would you like?
Take this money.
I'll leave my stuff with you for now
and pick it up later.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
Get out of the way!
Go!
Split up!
-OK! -OK!
This way.
Stop!
Kid,
these silly tricks of yours
won't help you get away.
Well, that was just a joke.
A joke before your death is not too much to ask.
Wait.
Come on out!
Stop playing tricks with me.
Come on, I know you're here!
Are you going to wait until I get hurt?
You brat.
Mr. Mo?
What are you doing here
instead of watching over Guanghui Bank?
Still talking rubbish when you're so dead?
How very arrogant.
Guys,
I want none of them left.
Could've left one to me.
You might as well stay out of this,
or it'd be too gory to clean up.
We would like you to tell Master Qi
to stop messing with Yuntai.
I'll be sure to tell him.
No need.
Upon seeing your body,
Qi will understand.
Were you so sure that I was tailing you?
Wen Cong died in Baiju Town,
and you were able to pass the buck.
But if I lose my life
in Nandu,
how will you explain it to Master?
You came to Guanghui Bank
knowing you were being shadowed
so that Qi Tianfeng would get suspicious of me.
Not bad, kid.
You risked your life
to make me kill those men of the Cao Sect,
for that way I could no longer stay out of this.
If you prefer to keep a low profile,
I'll be the one in the open, you stay in the background.
What do you say?
Do you know why Wen Cong ended up like that?
There're naturally ups and downs in the business world.
For years Wen Cong had been struggling
to compete with the Chamber of Commerce of Nandu.
But he wasn't willing to accept it
and wanted to make a comeback.
The Chamber of Commerce was in Mr. Wen's hands,
which means it was in the hands of Yuntai.
Mr. Wen was only serving the sect.
Why can't it
be in the hands of local merchants?
Why did it have to be Wen Cong?
You sound disrespectful to Yuntai's rules.
Kid,
if you want to team up with me,
consider talking to me nicely.
If you try to play tricks with me,
it'll only make me despise you.
Mo Bufan...
[Rongshun Tavern]
How did it go, Miss Shu?
I'm sorry. I screwed it up.
How do you mean?
I didn't get any money back,
but only these useless papers.
These are some merchants' proof of payment, right?
Why are you not at all surprised?
These are exactly what I wanted.
Why didn't you tell me so?
I-I asked you to collect debts
because it'd make you
go to more merchants when you can't get the money.
If I had asked you to collect
proof of payment,
you might have just slacked off.
Calm down.
I got it. Won't happen again.
Get out!
No problem.
Hurry up.
Wait.
What?
It's best if you can opt for a decent outfit tomorrow.
Don't be mad at me.
Consider it a small gift for you.
[Liansheng House Auction Day]
[Two years ago]
Stop following me.
Young Master.
Shouldn't you apologize
for your reckless driving?
It was my fault.
Please forgive me.
This is from Miss Ke, as compensation to you.
Menglan?
Still not ready.
Why is she so slow today?
What's wrong with you today?
Ten Taels of Gold...
Why are you dressed like a girl?
Why can't I?
But how will you fight?
Come on, have a try.
I can't when you're dressed like this.
Jin doesn't understand it.
I really like your look today.
It's like... Feminine charm concealing chivalry,
tenderness veiling a jade sword's blade.
How come I've never heard these verses before?
The ancients never met this person, this fine view,
so they weren't able to write these verses.
Enough, you two.
[Jingshui House]
What's the occasion?
Why are we here, joining the rich?
Today is Liansheng House's auction day.
Half of the merchants in Nandu are here.
The assets are being sold at a discount. It means profit.
The merchants wouldn't want to miss it.
But we're here...
[Meizhu, Tang family]
[Zhong, Tang family]
[Tang Xiao, Tang family]
That is Tang Xiao,
the leading figure in Nandu's gambling industry.
That woman looks rather aggressive.
The two bodyguards beside him
are said to be top masters.
That guy? I won't even have to go all out.
Today is about the auction.
Swords are of no use.
Show some restraint.
Su Mingyu will be here.
You're watching me?
What exactly are you planning?
To play it by ear.
Please enjoy.
Wait a minute.
Why is the food so unnecessarily exquisite?
This is far from enough.
Now,
get me two more portions of this.
Sure. Coming right up.
Young Master.
Qian.
So you came after all.
Your sister was right.
I'm just looking around.
Take care of yourself.
Mr. Su.
-Join us... -What are you doing here?
Jin.
Did you sleep well last night?
Miss Shu.
Miss Shu looks different today.
Looks strange, doesn't she?
Shut up!
You all get obsessed with Ke Menglan
when you see her,
and I can't dress like this?
Come on, have a seat.
OK.
Why?
I'm not obsessed.
Fellow Nandu merchants,
I hope you're well.
I'm honored to have been appointed by Chairman Su
to be the host of the auction today.
I'm sure you are eager to see the lots,
so I won't go on.
Let's get started then.
Yeah, let's get started.
Please bear with me, Mr. Tang.
We still need to spell out the rules.
As this is an auction,
when the gong sounds, the highest bidder gets the lot.
So please follow the way we do business
and let fate decide.
Miss.
Tomorrow,
the world outside will be the same,
but the future of Liansheng House is uncertain.
If it falls into the hands of Mr. Tang...
I met many like Tang Xiao
when I was in the brothel.
Miss,
there is an army of wealthy young men
who want to marry you.
If you can marry one that's somewhat to your liking,
it'd be better than being bullied by Tang Xiao.
We're of the low and degenerate lot.
It will always be a hard life.
Besides, the imperial government decreed that
this status must be kept for generations,
and we're not allowed to marry a commoner,
not even as a concubine,
but can only be slaves.
But Mr. Su does seem to be infatuated with you.
The third lot is Liansheng House.
We're starting at 1,200 taels of silver.
Please start bidding.
Thirteen hundred taels.
Thirteen hundred taels, by Table A2.
Fourteen hundred taels.
Sit down.
-Fourteen hundred taels, by Table C1. -Two thousand taels!
Two thousand taels, by Table A2.
If you're here for Liansheng House,
why aren't you bidding?
Do remember
to do the unexpected
and wait for the right time.
Two thousand taels, second time.
Three thousand taels.
Three thousand taels, by Table B2.
Mr. Qian,
the Su family is a respectable and wealthy family.
Since when are you so interested in these
niche businesses
with little profit?
Or are you trying to drive up the price?
Three thousand five hundred taels.
Mr. Tang,
please speak with caution.
Three thousand five hundred taels, by Table A2.
Three thousand five hundred taels, second time.
Can you lend me 1,000 taels?
I'll pay you back with interest within half a month.
Normally the interest rate is 3%.
For you, Mr. Su, I'll make it 1%.
Deal.
Four thousand taels.
Four thousand taels?
Have you really got 1,000 taels?
Four thousand taels, by Table B2.
Liansheng House
is worth no more than 3,000 taels
so far as market price goes,
right?
Mr. Su,
got a deep affection for it, eh?
Mr. Su is fond of it.
So am I.
What a coincidence!
Four thousand five hundred taels.
What are you waiting for?
Table A2
bids 4,500 taels.
Mr. Su,
if you want Liansheng House so much,
I could make an investment.
We can bid for it together.
OK.
Mr. Su bids 6,000 taels.
Six thousand taels, by Table B2.
Six thousand taels, second time.
Six thousand taels, third time.
May I know your name?
Why haven't I seen you before?
I'm Yun Xiang.
I'm new here.
Yun Xiang?
Nice to meet you.
This is Nandu.
I'm Tang Xiao.
There's someone over there!
Take Zhang Kui away now.
Give him a proper burial.
-OK. -OK.
You only found out a name?
There's nothing else?
Zhang Kui said that
although Yun Xiang was highly skilled in martial arts,
he had never demonstrated it.
When the news came yesterday
saying he was alone,
Kui immediately gathered the men.
Little did he know that it was Yun Xiang's trap.
The whole dozen men of ours just vanished.
Even if Yun Xiang had killed them all on his own,
he wouldn't have been able to clean it up so fast.
Yuntai probably has other supporters in Nandu.
Go prepare a banknote of 5,000 taels of silver
and bring it to the Tangs' Gambling House.
Master,
we gave them 3,000 taels of silver at most in previous years.
The extra 2,000 taels...
It's half a month's worth of our profit.
It's been decades.
I've had enough of relying on others.
That's the reason
we had to get rid of Wen Cong.